A Guide to the Henry County (Va.) Judgments, 1776-1930
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Henry County (Va.) Judgments, 1776-1930
Library of Virginia
1160600-1160743
65.25 cu. ft. (146 boxes)
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
These items came in a transfer of court papers from Henry County.
Historical Information
Henry County was formed in 1776 from Pittsylvania County.
The County Court was the original colonial court of adjudication and recordation, and it was the principal tribunal for the administration of local justice. The individual justices could act on small claims matters as well as criminal matters where imminent bodily harm was a possibility, there being an appeal to the full County Court, which met monthly. This court ceased to exist in 1904 and the recordation function was transferred to the circuit court.
The Superior Court of Law was created in 1808. It met twice a year in each county, presided over by a circuit-riding General Court judge. Records were filed with the County Court. It had civil and criminal jurisdiction. The court ceased to exist in 1831.
The Circuit Superior Courts of Law and Chancery, established in 1831, were the upper courts on the local level. Sessions were held twice a year in each county, presided over by a General Court judge. The counties were grouped into districts for the convenience of the judge. The court ceased to exist in 1851.
The Circuit Court was authorized by the Constitution of 1851 and established by an act of the General Assembly passed in May 1852. Courts were held twice yearly in each county, presided over by 21 judges who rode circuits in the area of their jurisdiction. The records were filed with County Court records. These courts were granted original jurisdiction concurrrent with that of the County Courts, as well as appellate jurisdiction in all civil cases of more than fifty dollars and criminal cases not "expressly cognizable in some other court," including those involving loss of life.
Scope and Content
Henry County (Va.) Judgments, 1776-1930, contain civil cases heard in County Court, Superior Court of Law, Circuit Superior Court, and Circuit Court in which justice was administered on the strictly formulated rules of common law. The majority of cases in this record series relate to matters of debt.
Arrangement
Chronological (Cases filed within each box by month and year they were resolved.)
Access Terms
Lancaster County (Va.) -- Circuit Court.; Lancaster County (Va.) -- Circuit Superior Court of Law and Chancery.; Lancaster County (Va.) -- County Court.; Lancaster County (Va.) -- Superior Court of Law.; Civil procedure -- Virginia -- Lancaster County.; Courts -- Virginia -- Lancaster County.; Debt -- Virginia -- Lancaster County.; Public Records -- Virginia -- Lancaster County.; Lancaster County (Va.) -- History.; Decisions -- Virginia -- Lancaster County.; Judicial records -- Virginia -- Lancaster County.; Local government records -- Virginia -- Lancaster County.
Contents List
- Judgments 1776-1784 (Barcode 1160600)
- Judgments 1784-1786 (Barcode 1160601)
- Judgments 1786-1787 (Barcode 1160603)
- Judgments 1786 (Barcode 1160602)
- Judgments 1787-1788 (Barcode 1160604)
- Judgments 1788 (Barcode 1160605)
- Judgments 1788-1789 (Barcode 1160606)
- Judgments 1789-1790 (Barcode 1160607)
- Judgments 1790-1791 (Barcode 1160608)
- Judgments 1791-1792 (Barcode 1160609)
- Judgments 1792-1793 (Barcode 1160610)
- Judgments 1794-1795 (Barcode 1160611)
- Judgments 1795-1796 (Barcode 1160612)
- Judgments 1796-1797 (Barcode 1160613)
- Judgments 1797-1799 (Barcode 1160614)
- Judgments 1799-1800 (Barcode 1160615)
- Judgments 1800-1801 (Barcode 1160616)
- Judgments 1801-1802 (Barcode 1160617)
- Judgments 1803-1806 (Barcode 1160618)
- Judgments 1806-1807 (Barcode 1160619)
- Judgments 1807-1808 (Barcode 1160620)
- Judgments 1808-1809 (Barcode 1160621)
- Judgments 1809-1810 (Barcode 1160622)
- Judgments 1810-1811 (Barcode 1160623)
- Judgments 1811-1812 (Barcode 1160624)
- Judgments 1812-1813 (Barcode 1160625)
- Judgments 1813-1814 (Barcode 1160626)
- Judgments 1814-1816 (Barcode 1160627)
- Judgments 1816-1818 (Barcode 1160628)
- Judgments 1818-1819 (Barcode 1160629)
- Judgments 1819 (Barcode 1160630)
- Judgments 1819-1820 (Barcode 1160631)
- Judgments 1820 (Barcode 1160632)
- Judgments 1820-1821 (Barcode 1160633)
- Judgments 1821-1822 (Barcode 1160635)
- Judgments 1821 (Barcode 1160634)
- Judgments 1822-1823 (Barcode 1160637)
- Judgments 1822 (Barcode 1160636)
- Judgments 1823-1824 (Barcode 1160638)
- Judgments 1824-1825 (Barcode 1160639)
- Judgments 1825 (Barcode 1160640)
- Judgments 1825-1826 (Barcode 1160641)
- Judgments 1826-1827 (Barcode 1160642)
- Judgments 1827 (Barcode 1160643)
- Judgments 1828 (Barcode 1160645)
- Judgments 1828-1829 (Barcode 1160646)
- Judgments 1828 (Barcode 1160644)
- Judgments 1829-1830 (Barcode 1160647)
- Judgments 1830 (Barcode 1160648)
- Judgments 1831 (Barcode 1160649)
- Judgments 1831-1832 (Barcode 1160650)
- Judgments 1832-1833 (Barcode 1160651)
- Judgments 1833-1834 (Barcode 1160652)
- Judgments 1834-1835 (Barcode 1160653)
- Judgments 1835-1836 (Barcode 1160654)
- Judgments 1837 (Barcode 1160655)
- Judgments 1838 (Barcode 1160656)
- Judgments 1838-1839 (Barcode 1160657)
- Judgments 1839-1840 (Barcode 1160658)
- Judgments 1840 (Barcode 1160659)
- Judgments 1840-1841 (Barcode 1160660)
- Judgments 1841-1842 (Barcode 1160661)
- Judgments 1842 (Barcode 1160662)
- Judgments 1842-1843 (Barcode 1160663)
- Judgments 1843 (Barcode 1160664)
- Judgments 1843-1844 (Barcode 1160665)
- Judgments 1844-1845 (Barcode 1160666)
- Judgments 1845-1846 (Barcode 1160667)
- Judgments 1846 (Barcode 1160668)
- Judgments 1846-1847 (Barcode 1160669)
- Judgments 1847-1848 (Barcode 1160670)
- Judgments 1848 (Barcode 1160671)
- Judgments 1848-1849 (Barcode 1160672)
- Judgments 1849-1850 (Barcode 1160673)
- Judgments 1850 (Barcode 1160674)
- Judgments 1850-1851 (Barcode 1160675)
- Judgments 1851-1852 (Barcode 1160676)
- Judgments 1852-1853 (Barcode 1160677)
- Judgments 1853-1854 (Barcode 1160678)
- Judgments 1854-1855 (Barcode 1160679)
- Judgments 1855-1856 (Barcode 1160680)
- Judgments 1856 (Barcode 1160681)
- Judgments 1856-1857 (Barcode 1160682)
- Judgments 1857 (Barcode 1160683)
- Judgments 1857-1858 (Barcode 1160684)
- Judgments 1858 (Barcode 1160686)
- Judgments 1858 (Barcode 1160687)
- Judgments 1858 (Barcode 1160685)
- Judgments 1858-1859 (Barcode 1160688)
- Judgments 1859-1860 (Barcode 1160690)
- Judgments 1859 (Barcode 1160689)
- Judgments 1860-1861 (Barcode 1160693)
- Judgments 1860 (Barcode 1160691)
- Judgments 1860 (Barcode 1160692)
- Judgments 1861 (Barcode 1160694)
- Judgments 1861-1864 (Barcode 1160695)
- Judgments 1864-1866 (Barcode 1160696)
- Judgments 1866 (Barcode 1160697)
- Judgments 1866-1867 (Barcode 1160698)
- Judgments 1867 (Barcode 1160699)
- Judgments 1867-1868 (Barcode 1160700)
- Judgments 1868-1869 (Barcode 1160706)
- Judgments 1868 (Barcode 1160705)
- Judgments 1868 (Barcode 1160702)
- Judgments 1868 (Barcode 1160703)
- Judgments 1868 (Barcode 1160704)
- Judgments 1868 (Barcode 1160701)
- Judgments 1869 (Barcode 1160707)
- Judgments 1869-1870 (Barcode 1160708)
- Judgments 1870 (Barcode 1160709)
- Judgments 1870-1871 (Barcode 1160710)
- Judgments 1871 (Barcode 1160711)
- Judgments 1872 (Barcode 1160712)
- Judgments 1872-1873 (Barcode 1160713)
- Judgments 1873-1874 (Barcode 1160714)
- Judgments 1874 (Barcode 1160715)
- Judgments 1875 (Barcode 1160716)
- Judgments 1875-1876 (Barcode 1160717)
- Judgments 1876-1877 (Barcode 1160718)
- Judgments 1877-1878 (Barcode 1160719)
- judgments 1878-1886 (Barcode 1016406)
- Judgments 1878-1879 (Barcode 1160721)
- Judgments 1878 (Barcode 1160720)
- Judgments 1879-1880 (Barcode 1160722)
- Judgments 1880-1881 (Barcode 1160723)
- Judgments 1881-1882 (Barcode 1160724)
- Judgments 1882-1884 (Barcode 1160725)
- Judgments 1884-1885 (Barcode 1160726)
- Judgments 1885-1886 (Barcode 1160727)
- Judgments 1886-1887 (Barcode 1160728)
- Judgments 1887-1888 (Barcode 1160729)
- Judgments 1888-1889 (Barcode 1160730)
- Judgments 1889-1890 (Barcode 1160731)
- Judgments 1890-1891 (Barcode 1160732)
- Judgments 1891-1892 (Barcode 1160733)
- Judgments 1892-1893 (Barcode 1160734)
- Judgments 1893-1894 (Barcode 1160735)
- Judgments 1894-1895 (Barcode 1160736)
- Judgments 1895-1896 (Barcode 1160737)
- Judgments 1896-1897 (Barcode 1160738)
- Judgments 1897-1899 (Barcode 1160739)
- Judgments 1899 (Barcode 1160740)
- Judgments 1900-1902 (Barcode 1160741)
- Judgments 1902-1904 (Barcode 1160742)
- Judgments 1904-1930 (Barcode 1160743)